<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://cppalliance.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://cppalliance.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-03T14:09:21+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The C++ Alliance</title><subtitle>The C++ Alliance is dedicated to helping the C++ programming language evolve. We see it developing as an ecosystem of open source libraries and as a growing community of those who contribute to those libraries..</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Initial Work On Certify Complete</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/10/24/Initial-work-on-Certify-complete.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Initial Work On Certify Complete" /><published>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/10/24/Initial-work-on-Certify-complete</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/10/24/Initial-work-on-Certify-complete.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;initial-work-on-certify-complete&quot;&gt;Initial work on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Certify&lt;/code&gt; complete&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been mentioned in my initial blog post that I’d be working on a TLS
certificate store abstraction library, with the intent of submitting it for
formal review for Boost, at some point in the (hopefully near) future.
The initial setup phase (things that every Software Engineer hates) is more
or less complete. CI setup was a bit tricky - getting OpenSSL to run with
the boost build system on both Windows and Linux (and in the future MacOS)
has provided a lot of “fun” thanks to the inherent weirdness of OpenSSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test harness currently consists of two test runners that loads certificates
from a database (big name for a folder structure stored in git) that has the
certificate chains divided into two groups. Chains that will fail due to various
reasons (e.g. self-signed certificates, wrong domain name) and ones that will pass
(when using a valid certificate store). I’m still working on checking whether
the failure was for the expected reason. All the verification is done offline
(i.e. no communication with external servers is performed, only chain verification).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point it looks like I should consider, whether the current design of
the verification code is a good approach. Using the verification callback
from OpenSSL and asio::ssl is quite an easy way of integrating the platform-specific
certificate store API it causes issues with error propagation (transporting a platform-specific
error through OpenSSL) and may be fairly slow, because it requires certificates to be
reencdoded into the DER format so that they can be fed into the platform-specific API.
An alternative to this approach would be load the entire root certificate store, along with CRLs and
OCSP configuration into an OpenSSL context. This is potentially a little bit harder to get right but
may offer better performance (no reencoding required when veryfing certificate chains) and eliminates
the issues related to error handling. Further investigation, as to which approach is better, is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to star the repository: https://github.com/djarek/certify!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Initial work on Certify complete It’s been mentioned in my initial blog post that I’d be working on a TLS certificate store abstraction library, with the intent of submitting it for formal review for Boost, at some point in the (hopefully near) future. The initial setup phase (things that every Software Engineer hates) is more or less complete. CI setup was a bit tricky - getting OpenSSL to run with the boost build system on both Windows and Linux (and in the future MacOS) has provided a lot of “fun” thanks to the inherent weirdness of OpenSSL. The test harness currently consists of two test runners that loads certificates from a database (big name for a folder structure stored in git) that has the certificate chains divided into two groups. Chains that will fail due to various reasons (e.g. self-signed certificates, wrong domain name) and ones that will pass (when using a valid certificate store). I’m still working on checking whether the failure was for the expected reason. All the verification is done offline (i.e. no communication with external servers is performed, only chain verification). At this point it looks like I should consider, whether the current design of the verification code is a good approach. Using the verification callback from OpenSSL and asio::ssl is quite an easy way of integrating the platform-specific certificate store API it causes issues with error propagation (transporting a platform-specific error through OpenSSL) and may be fairly slow, because it requires certificates to be reencdoded into the DER format so that they can be fed into the platform-specific API. An alternative to this approach would be load the entire root certificate store, along with CRLs and OCSP configuration into an OpenSSL context. This is potentially a little bit harder to get right but may offer better performance (no reencoding required when veryfing certificate chains) and eliminates the issues related to error handling. Further investigation, as to which approach is better, is required. Don’t forget to star the repository: https://github.com/djarek/certify!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gold Sponsor Of Cppcon 2018</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/09/23/Gold-sponsor-of-Cppcon-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gold Sponsor Of Cppcon 2018" /><published>2018-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/09/23/Gold-sponsor-of-Cppcon-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/09/23/Gold-sponsor-of-Cppcon-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;
The Alliance is a Gold sponsor for
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cppcon.org/history/2018/&quot;&gt;CppCon 2018&lt;/a&gt;. This
conference is the annual, week-long face-to-face gathering for the
entire C++ community. The conference is organized by the C++ community
for the community. Attendees enjoy inspirational talks and a friendly
atmosphere designed to help individuals learn from each other, meet
interesting people, and generally have a stimulating experience.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Alliance is a Gold sponsor for CppCon 2018. This conference is the annual, week-long face-to-face gathering for the entire C++ community. The conference is organized by the C++ community for the community. Attendees enjoy inspirational talks and a friendly atmosphere designed to help individuals learn from each other, meet interesting people, and generally have a stimulating experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Damian Jarek Joins As Staff Engineer</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/09/03/Damian-Jarek-joins-as-staff-engineer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Damian Jarek Joins As Staff Engineer" /><published>2018-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/09/03/Damian-Jarek-joins-as-staff-engineer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company,/damian/2018/09/03/Damian-Jarek-joins-as-staff-engineer.html">&lt;p&gt;Damian Jarek joins the Alliance as Staff Engineer. Previously he worked on a
number of embedded networking projects for a few major clients. As a Staff
Engineer he’ll be working on an open-source companion library for Boost.Beast
and Boost.Asio, which will abstract away the platform-specific details of
acessing system proxy settings and performing TLS verification of a peer
certificate chain using the operating system’s key store.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Damian Jarek joins the Alliance as Staff Engineer. Previously he worked on a number of embedded networking projects for a few major clients. As a Staff Engineer he’ll be working on an open-source companion library for Boost.Beast and Boost.Asio, which will abstract away the platform-specific details of acessing system proxy settings and performing TLS verification of a peer certificate chain using the operating system’s key store.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marshall Clow joins as a Staff Engineer</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company,/marshall/2018/08/13/Marshall-Clow-joins-as-staff-engineer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marshall Clow joins as a Staff Engineer" /><published>2018-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company,/marshall/2018/08/13/Marshall-Clow-joins-as-staff-engineer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company,/marshall/2018/08/13/Marshall-Clow-joins-as-staff-engineer.html">&lt;p&gt;Marshall Clow joins the Alliance as a Staff Engineer. Previously,
he worked at Qualcomm for many years. Most of his time is spent
working on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://libcxx.llvm.org&quot;&gt;libc++&lt;/a&gt;,
the C++ standard library implementation for LLVM. He is also a member
of the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://isocpp.org/std/the-committee&quot;&gt;C++ standards committee&lt;/a&gt;,
currently serving as the chair of LWG, the library working group.
Marshall has been contributing to the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boost.org&quot;&gt;Boost libraries&lt;/a&gt;
since 2001, and is the author of the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://boost.org/libs/algorithm&quot;&gt;Boost.Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;
library. Furthermore he maintains several other boost libraries,
and moderates some of the boost mailing lists. Finally, Marshall
has graciously taken on the role of release manager for several
Boost versions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Marshall Clow joins the Alliance as a Staff Engineer. Previously, he worked at Qualcomm for many years. Most of his time is spent working on libc++, the C++ standard library implementation for LLVM. He is also a member of the C++ standards committee, currently serving as the chair of LWG, the library working group. Marshall has been contributing to the Boost libraries since 2001, and is the author of the Boost.Algorithm library. Furthermore he maintains several other boost libraries, and moderates some of the boost mailing lists. Finally, Marshall has graciously taken on the role of release manager for several Boost versions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Law Firm for Non-Profits engaged</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/08/06/The-Law-Firm-for-Non-Profits-engaged.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Law Firm for Non-Profits engaged" /><published>2018-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/08/06/The-Law-Firm-for-Non-Profits-engaged</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/08/06/The-Law-Firm-for-Non-Profits-engaged.html">&lt;p&gt;The Alliance engages
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lfnp.com/&quot;&gt;The Law Firm for Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt;
for legal representation and services. They are passionate about
supporting, advocating for and partnering with non-profits and the
people behind them. For more than three decades, those looking for
assistance with non-profit law throughout the United States and
around the world have relied on the attorneys of The Law Firm
for Non-Profits for superior legal and business guidance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Alliance engages The Law Firm for Non-Profits for legal representation and services. They are passionate about supporting, advocating for and partnering with non-profits and the people behind them. For more than three decades, those looking for assistance with non-profit law throughout the United States and around the world have relied on the attorneys of The Law Firm for Non-Profits for superior legal and business guidance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Member Of The International Committee For Information Technology Standards</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/30/Member-of-the-international-committee-for-information-technology-standards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member Of The International Committee For Information Technology Standards" /><published>2018-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/30/Member-of-the-international-committee-for-information-technology-standards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/30/Member-of-the-international-committee-for-information-technology-standards.html">&lt;p&gt;The Alliance is member of the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.incits.org/&quot;&gt;International Committee for Information Technology Standards&lt;/a&gt;.
INCITS is the central U.S. forum dedicated to creating technology standards
for the next generation of innovation. INCITS members combine their expertise
to create the building blocks for globally transformative technologies. From
cloud computing to communications, from transportation to health care
technologies, INCITS is the place where innovation begins. Membership in
INCITS allows voting in official WG21 meetings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Alliance is member of the International Committee for Information Technology Standards. INCITS is the central U.S. forum dedicated to creating technology standards for the next generation of innovation. INCITS members combine their expertise to create the building blocks for globally transformative technologies. From cloud computing to communications, from transportation to health care technologies, INCITS is the place where innovation begins. Membership in INCITS allows voting in official WG21 meetings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gold sponsor of C++Now</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/06/Gold-sponsor-of-C++-Now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gold sponsor of C++Now" /><published>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/06/Gold-sponsor-of-C++-Now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/05/06/Gold-sponsor-of-C++-Now.html">&lt;p&gt;The Alliance is a Gold sponsor for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cppnow.org/history/2018/&quot;&gt;C++Now 2018&lt;/a&gt;. This
conference is a gathering of C++ experts and enthusiasts from around
the world in beautiful Aspen, Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Alliance is a Gold sponsor for C++Now 2018. This conference is a gathering of C++ experts and enthusiasts from around the world in beautiful Aspen, Colorado.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Corporate Logo Is Adopted</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/02/22/Corporate-logo-is-adopted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corporate Logo Is Adopted" /><published>2018-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/02/22/Corporate-logo-is-adopted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company/2018/02/22/Corporate-logo-is-adopted.html">&lt;p&gt;
A new corporate logo is adopted from the conclusion of a contest on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.designhill.com/&quot;&gt;Designhill&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2018-02-22-Corporate-logo-is-adopted.png&quot; width=&quot;267&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A new corporate logo is adopted from the conclusion of a contest on Designhill:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jon Kalb Joins The Board</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company,/jon/2018/01/16/Jon-Kalb-joins-the-board.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jon Kalb Joins The Board" /><published>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company,/jon/2018/01/16/Jon-Kalb-joins-the-board</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company,/jon/2018/01/16/Jon-Kalb-joins-the-board.html">&lt;p&gt;Jon Kalb joins the Alliance board of directors as treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jon Kalb joins the Alliance board of directors as treasurer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">René Rivera Joins The Board</title><link href="http://cppalliance.org/company,/rene/2018/01/16/Ren%C3%A9-Rivera-joins-the-board.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="René Rivera Joins The Board" /><published>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cppalliance.org/company,/rene/2018/01/16/Ren%C3%A9-Rivera-joins-the-board</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cppalliance.org/company,/rene/2018/01/16/Ren%C3%A9-Rivera-joins-the-board.html">&lt;p&gt;René Rivera joins the Alliance board of directors as secretary.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">René Rivera joins the Alliance board of directors as secretary.</summary></entry></feed>